okay so let's look at the solution for
this part of the quiz do we dispatch an
instruction in cycle five no we do not
all of these instructions are waiting
for something to be broadcast
so until we actually broadcast some
results and these instructions can
capture the values
they will not be able to dispatch both
of them are waiting for something
so this should be empty
do we write any results
yes
the instruction in rob3 is an ad it
began executing in cycle 4
it takes one cycle to execute so in
cycle 5 it will write its result so the
correct answer here is rob3 this is
which instruction writes its result in
cycle 5. as a result of this
right result in cycle 5
we mark this rob3 entry as done
the value of 3 is broadcast with the tag
of rob3 it gets captured here because
this instruction is waiting for up3
so in fact
because we can dispatch this instruction
in the same cycle in cycle 5 this
subtract does dispatch
so the instruction in rob 5 will
dispatch
and it will begin executing in cycle 6.
so this is somewhat of a trick question
because you needed to first figure out
that this right result happens and as a
result of this we enable the dispatch of
this instruction so it's kind of
interesting in that in this cycle this
instruction has been issued capture the
result and dispatched